

Kody **Brown**

Software Architect

CONTACT ME



(801) 310-1122



kody@vutiliti.com vutiliti.com



KE7ZIU



7065 S 5490 W West Jordan, UT 84081

LINKS

GitHub, LinkedIn, Twitter, G+, FB kodybrown

SKYPE

wasatchwizard

WEB

kodybrown.com wasatchwizard.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

UI/UX Design
HTML5
CSS3
JavaScript
Responsive Web
C# / ASP.NET



ABOUT ME

I am passionate about technology in all of its various forms. From running a large network of Bitcoin miners, building go-karts and electric scooters, playing with amateur (ham) radio, to converting a 40-foot school bus to a mobile hacker station and RV for the family. I am exceptionally skilled across the full stack of software development and Internet of Things (IoT) devices.

I take pride in transforming complex challenges into simple and elegant solutions, while maintaining an intuitive user experience. I can focus on the big picture while pacing myself and teams through the iterative development process, ensuring stable and extendable solutions.



EDUCATION

Business Management University of Phoenix

2002 - 2003

Robotics & Fabrication, Software Engineering Modesto Junior College

1992 - 1994



BUZZWORTHY

Graduated high school early

Graduated high school at 15 years old and started attending college.

Essential C#

One of the technical editors of (three editions of) the Essential C# book by Mark Michaelis.

Patent #8,275,895

Steve Ellis and I are co-authors of "DHCP – Systems and methods for establishing a trusted dynamic host configuration protocol connection."

WORK EXPERIENCE

Vutiliti, Inc.

Chief Technology Officer

2015 - Present

Created responsive, mobile-first websites using Angular.js and services in ASP.NET Web API and Go, while utilizing Docker and AWS/Azure. Worked with partners to solve enterprise issues using custom hardware and software.

ConsultNet 2013 - 2016

Web Architect (Consultant)

Created responsive websites using Angular.js, Sitecore CMS, Node, Meteor, PhoneGap, Ember.js, and ASP.NET MVC while constantly adjusting to different teams, environments, and schedules.

Venafi, Inc. 2008 - 2013

Web Architect

Led a team of six developers in the design and implementation of a webbased PKI management console for Fortune 100 companies. Worked closely with the UI/UX lead to create a stunning and extremely friendly user interface. I also focused a majority of my time on XSS and CSRF prevention.

OneGreatFamily.com Web Architect

2006 - 2008

Led a team of four developers in creating a web-based genealogy website, including an online family tree, extensible dashboard, and widgets.

LANDesk Software, Inc. Senior Software Engineer

Worked on the ISV team in different areas of development. From Classic ASP to C#/ASP.NET, and Windows CE/Mobile (C++) and BlackBerry (J2ME) devices. Created LANDesk Message-based SDK and Handheld Manager (which had over 1 million client installs).